Subject Files
Marist Archives and Special Collections
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  - Subject files: First World Flight, 1924; 4 (Box 1544)
    - Verso [: THE AVIATORS WORST JINX-FLOWERS. At Vancouver, Wash..in the first stage of the world flight, Mayor George L. Balter of Portland, Cre (?), presented boquets of Portland roses to the air Magelians (?). Left to right are Lieut. Oakley Kelly, commander of the field (?) Lieut. Smith, Maj. Martin, Mayor Balter, Lieut. Wade, Lieut Arnold, and L.V. Jenkins, the Portland chief of police., 25-verso
    - [Mothers of Flyers watching the sky], 26
    - Verso [: Mothers of Flyers. L. to R.- Mrs. Jasper Smith and Mrs. Roberta Harding.], 26-verso
    - [Lieut. Smith's parents greeting their son during the First World Flight.], 27
    - Verso: Lieut Smith - Mother and Father; ROUND-THE-WORLD FLIERS REACH SAN DIEGO, The round the world flyers reached Rockwell fiield[sic], San Diego, where their machines were put through mechanical tests prior to the hop-off six months ago, on September 22. This picture shows Lieut. Lowell Smith, commander of the flight, greeted by his father and mother, Mr. and Mrs. Jasper Smith, just after their arrical at Rockwell Field., 27-verso
    - [Lieut. Wade receiving Boston II from Lieut. MacDonald during the First World Flight], 28
    - Verso: Lieut Wade receiving Boston II from Lieut. MacDonald; "Happy" Leigh Wade, in center, taking over from Lieut. George C. MacDonald, right, the command of the Boston II, which replaced his own, the Boston I, which crashed in the North Atlantic near the Orkney Islands., 28-verso
    - [Lieut. Leslie Arnold-First World Flier], 29
    - Verso [:Lieut. Leslie Arnold, originally an alternate pilot for the world s flight, teamed up with Lieut. Lowell Smith at Seattle, acting as Smith s mechanician. His opportunity came when Smith s aid, Sergt. Turner, suddenly became ill. Pacific Atlantic photo.], 29-verso
    - [Lieut. Erik Nelson-First World Flier], 30
    - Verso [:Left behind when his mates hopped off at Clover field because his ship was not ready, Lieut. Erik Nelson made a nonstop flight of 775 miles to join them at Seattle. That was the second longest hop of the whole world's tour. Pacific & Atlantic photo.], 30-verso
    - [Three First World Flight planes in Alaska], 31
    - Verso [NATURE MAKES THEM MIGHTY SMALL. Photo shows three of the world flight planes moored in an Alaskan harbor..The background of ice capped mountains vividly portrays the smallness of man made machines when compared with nature.], 31-verso
    - [President Coolidge greeting fliers during the First World Flight], 32
    - Verso: Pres. Coolidge greeting fliers; President Coolidge Greeting Lieutenant Smith on the Fliers' Triumphant Return, 32-verso
    - [The First World Flight cruiser, Boston], 33
    - Verso: The world cruiser Boston, which lost its nose while being tuned up at Prince Rupert. Until it crashed finally almost on the last leg of the trip, the Boston flew with a makeshift cowl made of copper., 33-verso
    - [Men standing by a camel in front of an airplane used in the Flirst World Flight], 34
  - Subject files: First World Flight, 1924; 5 (Box 1544)
    - [Lowell Thomas (?) and another aviator in a biplane during the First World Flight], 1
    - [First World Flight plane], 2
    - [Airplane used in ther First World Flight], 3
    - Verso [:On our way to Hong Kong (?) flew over the Ladrones, of Thieves Islands.], 3-verso
    - [Planes in the First World Flight moored on the shore], 4
    - Verso: "To protect the planes from the 'Willie-was' we hauled them up on runways.", 4-verso
    - [Planes in the First World Flight flying over elephants (?)], 5
    - Verso [: In the jungles over which they flew were elephant herds, tiger and ferocious sladang (?).], 5-verso
    - [Erik Nelson-First World Flier], 6
    - Verso [: When Erik Nelson got through the fog and flew on to Iceland, had ample reason to smile.], 6-verso
    - [Plane in the First World Flight flying over mountains], 7
    - [Wade-First World Flier], 8
    - Verso [: Fresh from the triumphs of the Pacific, Wade little dreamed of the trouble he used to encounter on the way to Iceland.], 8-verso
    - [Three men from the First World Flight standing in front of a plane], 9
    - [Three planes in the First World Flight flying over Delhi], 10
    - Verso [: On the flight from Allahabad to Ambala the passed over the seven ruined cities of Delhi.], 10-verso
    - [Three First World Flight planes], 11
    - [Planes in the First World Flight flying over a village], 12
    - Verso [: Between Hong Kong and Bangkok they passed over scores of villages perched on stilts.], 12-verso
    - [Man and woman holding a sign saying, "Erik and Bunny are gonna get Married!"], 13
    - [And old car and two men sitting in a plane], 14
    - [Group of men involded in the First World Flight (?)], 15
    - [Drawing of an aviator (?)], 16
    - [Two children standing by the wheel of a plane during the First World Flight], 17
    - [Two pilots-First World Flight], 18
    - [Lowell Thomas and Lt. CC Moseley (?) First World Flight], 19
    - Verso [L.T. and Lt. CC Moseley; F.W. Flight], 19-verso
    - [Smith and Nelson (?)-First World Fliers], 20
    - Verso [: Smith and Nelson enjoying Griddle cakes and coffee at Mere Point, Maine.], 20-verso
    - [Lieutenant Leslie Arnold and his compantion-First World Flier], 21
    - Verso [The Wold Flight Commander (in sweater) Lieutenant Arnold, his compantion, and the ship in which theygirdled the Earth.], 21-verso
    - [Four planes lined up to take flight during the First World Flight], 22
    - Verso [: Ready for the final flight across India from Multan to Karachi.], 22-verso
    - [Captain Burdette S. Wright-First World Flier], 23
    - Verso [Caption Burdette S. Wright. (?) Office in the United States, 23-verso
    - [Lieutenant Leslie P. Arnold-First World Flier], 24
    - Verso [: Lieutenant Leslie P. Arnold], 24-verso
    - [Portrait of an American aviator (?) in uniform], 25
    - [Lieutenant Erik H. Nelson-First World Flier], 26
    - Verso [: Lieutenant Erik H. Nelson], 26-verso
    - [Lieutenant Lowell H. Smith-First World Flier], 27
    - Verso [: Lieutenant Lowell H. Smith], 27-verso
    - [Nelson Announcement Party], 28
    - Verso [Round the world flight-Nelson, Wade, Smith, Hardine (?), Arnold, Pricilla Dean, Bunny Butler, Moseley, V. Mosely, V.B., Butler-Nelson Announcement Party-C.C. Moseley's home November 1924.], 28-verso
    - [A man and an officer shaking hands], 29
    - [Pine tree and mountain landscape-First World Flight], 30
    - [Pine trees and snowy mountains-First World Flight], 31
    - [Lowell Thomas (?) and two other men standing with soldiers during the First World Flight], 32
    - [Harbor-First World Flight], 33
    - [Lowell Thomas (on left?) looking at a man and a woman in front of a car], 34
    - [Group of men standing with two cars], 35
    - [Lowell Thomas and other men standing with soldiers during the First World Flight], 36
    - [Lowell Thomas and a group of people standing outside of a house], 37
  - Subject files: First World Flight, 1924; 6 (Box 1544)
    - [Lowell Thomas (in middle) standing with a group of aviators in the First World Flight], 1
    - [Lieutenant Wade and General Brancker of the First World Flight shaking hands], 2
    - Verso [: THE AMERICAN WORLD FLIGHT. The three American aeroplanes landed at Croydon today (Wed) and were given a rousing reception by a large crowd. Photo shows. Lt. WADE, one of the pilots, shaking hands with General BRANCKER, Direcor of Civil Aviation.], 2-verso
    - [Woman pinning a flower on an aviator's jacket-The First World Flight], 3
    - [Three planes of the First World Flight sitting on the shore], 4
    - [Airplanes of the First World Flight flying over snowy mountains], 5
    - [Airplane in the First World Flight sitting on the water], 6
    - [A man and an aviator of the First World Flight], 7
    - [Crowd gathered at Santa Monica awaiting take-off during the First World Flight], 8
    - Verso [: At Santa Monica before the take-off], 8-verso
    - [Airplane in the First World Flight flying over water], 9
    - [An aviator in the First World Flight], 10
    - [A member of the First World FLight holding an aviator's hat], 11
    - [Two First World Flight planes in flight connected by a cord], 12
    - [Two aviators (?) of the First World Flight], 13
    - [An aviator of the First World Flight], 14
    - [Three planes of the First World Flight flying over houses on stilts], 15
    - [The Boston airplane of the First World Flight sinking in the ocean], 16
    - Verso [Sinking of the Boston (?) 1924 (?).], 16-verso
    - [Aviator involved in the First World Flight], 17
    - [Aviator in the First World Flight looking at a globe], 18
    - [Aviator involved in the First World Flight looking at a globe], 19
    - [Aviator in the First World Flight], 20
    - [Portrait of an aviator involved in the First World Flight], 21
    - [An aviator from the First World Flight], 22
    - [Aviators from the First World Flight standing in front of a plane], 23
    - [Two aviators involved in the First World Flight], 24
  - Subject files: First World Flight, 1924; 7 (Box 1544)
    - [Airplane from the First World Flight floating in water], 1
    - Verso [A forced landing of the Chicago in French Indo-China.], 1-verso
    - [First World Fliers arrival in Tokyo], 2
    - Verso [After many weeks of battling storms, cold, and ice, the United States world flyers finally arrived in the land of lotus blossoms and civilization again. Photograph shows part of the reception crowd which greeted the flyers on their arrival in Tokio.], 2-verso
    - [Donald Douglas], 3
    - Verso [Donald Douglas engineer who built the planes in which man first circumnavigated the world by air.], 3-verso
    - [Two aviators from the First World Flight holding monkeys (?)], 4
    - [Aviators Smith, Erik, and Leigh], 5
    - Verso [Smith, Erik, and Leigh preparing for the flight to Iceland and Greenland.], 5-verso
    - [First World Flight planes flying over the Irawaddi Delta], 6
    - Verso [Flying low and fast over the rice boats of the Irawaddi delta on the way to Akyab.], 6-verso
    - [Aviators of the First World Flight], 7
    - Verso [On their way east the airmen got still another thrill crossing the Cascase Range in the swaying cab of a "Milwaukee"electric flyer.], 7-verso
    - [Officer Clayton Bissell beaching supplies for the Fliers in Alaska], 8
    - Verso [Advance officer Clayton Bissell beaching supplies for the Fliers in Alaska.], 8-verso
    - [Ship with three First World Flight airplanes in the background], 9
    - Verso [With 3 airplanes (?) 3 (?) in sky], 9-verso
    - [Ship in Greenland], 10
    - Verso [The arrival at Ivigtut, Greenland.], 10-verso
    - [Two children in the Land of the Midnight Sun], 11
    - [View of Paris from a World Cruiser], 12
    - Verso ["So this is Paris?"A birdseye view of Montmartre from a World Cruiser. "We circled around over Paris several times before decending on Le Bourget aerodrome."], 12-verso
    - [First World Flight: Past the bad lands of Baluchistan], 13
    - Verso [Past the bad lands of Baluchistan.], 13-verso
    - [First World Flight plane flying through the Taurus Mountains], 14
    - Verso [Through the Taurus Mountains on our way from Alleppo to the Golden Horn.], 14-verso
    - [British plane flying over the Persian Gulf], 15
    - Verso [British aviators patrol the skies above the traditional home of Adam and Eve and above the waters of Adams Persian Gulf.], 15-verso
    - [First World Flight: Flying over islands], 16
    - Verso [Flying over "islands of opal that float on silver seas," with here and there "pale ports of amber and golden argosies."], 16-verso
    - [First World Flight planes flyiver over junk boats in the Yellow Sea], 17
    - Verso [: The end of man's first flight across the Yellow Sea.], 17-verso
    - [View of two First World Flight planes in flight], 18
    - [First World Fliers first look at Siberia], 19
    - Verso [The Fliers''first view of Siberia.], 19-verso
    - [Man Shanghai eating lunch], 20
    - Verso: Spectators in Shanghai brought their lunch, 20-verso
    - [First World Flight plane over a small town], 21
  - Subject files: First World Flight, 1924; 8 (Box 1544)
    - [First World Fliers over Benares], 1
    - Verso [:Circling over the holy city of Benares.], 1-verso
    - [Grandma Jongg], 2
    - Verso [:Grandma Jongg couldn't see how we could fly without flapping our wings.], 2-verso
    - [Three First World Flight planes over mountain forests], 3
    - [First World Flier in water], 4
    - Verso [: Lacatelli's ill-fated monoplane], 4-verso
    - [Two First World Flight planes], 5
    - Verso [Copyright by Sr. A. Erickson], 5-verso
    - [First World Flight plane over the Ganges River], 6
    - Verso [Up the sacred Ganges past the jute milles of the "second city of the British Empire".], 6-verso
    - [First World Flight planes over rice fields], 7
    - Verso [: Through stormy skies, over rice fields and jungle.], 7-verso
    - [Eskimos in kayaks going to meet the First World Fliers], 8
    - Verso [The Eskimo who came out to meet us in their kayaks had never seen an airplane before.], 8-verso
    - [A crowd gathered to meet the First World Fliers], 9
    - [First World Fliers working on the engine of their plane], 10
    - [Man involved in the First World Flight], 11
    - [Aviator in the First World Flight], 12
    - [Aviator involved in the First World Flight], 13
    - [Aviator involved in the First World Flight], 14
    - [Aviator involved in the First World Flight], 15
    - [Aviator involved in the First World Flight standing in front of a plane], 16
    - [Aviator involved in the First World Flight], 17
    - [Aviator involved in the First World Flight], 18
    - [Aviator involved in the First World Flight], 19
    - [Aviator involved in the First World Flight], 20
    - [First World Flight members in front of a plane], 21
    - [First World Fliers standing in front of a plane], 22
    - [Crowd in Paris gathered around the First World Fliers], 23
    - Verso [: Parisians welcioming the Fliers at Le Bourget.], 23-verso
    - [First World Flight plane in the water], 24
    - [People in kayaks rowing out to meet the First World Flier plane], 25
    - [First World Fliers rowing to shore], 26
    - Verso [:Flight Commander Lowell Smith was the first to set foot on American soil.], 26-verso
    - [First World Fliers Erik and "Hank"in Paris], 27
    - Verso [: Erik and "Hank"were still wearing short pants when landed at Paris.], 27-verso
    - [Two children in the Land of the Midnight Sun], 28
    - Verso [: Children of the Land of the Midnight Sun, fat as blubber and with faces like basket balls.], 28-verso
    - [Eskimo in a kayak (from First World Flight)], 29
    - Verso [:"Our Eskimo friend, whose name sounded like 'I-Sucka-Mukluk (?)'who loops-the-loop in his boat.", 29-verso
    - [First World Flight plane going up the Mekong], 30
    - Verso [: On our way up the Mekong and across the jungles from Cochinchina to Siam.], 30-verso
    - [Japanese people welcoming the First World Fliers.], 31
    - Verso [:"The Japanese welcomed us by waving American flags and singling 'My Country Tis of Thee' in English."], 31-verso
    - [View of an island from the cockpit of a First World Flight plane], 32
    - [First World Flight plane flying over ships], 33
    - [First World Fliers over palm trees], 34
    - Verso [: From Arctic to Tropic on man's first flight around the world.], 34-verso
    - [First World Flight plane], 35
    - Verso [: All the way from the English Channel, Ogden wig-wagged soft nothings to a flapper in a neighboring Pullman plane.], 35-verso
    - [Wade and Ogden awaiting rescue in the North Atlantic], 36
    - Verso [: Wade and Ogden awaiting rescue in the North Atlantic.], 36-verso
    - [First World Flier plane saoring above the ocean], 37
    - [First World Flight planes above mountains and houses], 38
    - [First World Fliers over the Spire of Shwe Dagon], 39
    - Verso [: Past the gold-and-jewelled Spire of Shwe Dagon, on their way from Rangoon to Hindustan.], 39-verso
    - [Small islands in the ocean: First World Flight], 40
    - [Mount Katmai, Alaska], 41
    - Verso [: WORLD'S MOST ACTIVE VOLCANO. The world flyers winged their way close to Mount Katmai, Alaska, on their way to Seward and wanted to explore it, but their schedule demanded that they push on.], 41-verso
    - [First World Flight planes over junk boats in China], 42
    - Verso [: Along the China cost they flew past many wired (weird) junks.], 42-verso
    - [Lieut. Henry H. Ogden and his pet racoon], 43
    - Verso [: Lieut henry H. Ogden and his pet racoon.], 43-verso
    - [The First World Fliers ready to start their trip around the world], 44
    - Verso [: Ready for the Start. Left to right. Sergeant Turmen, Sergeant Ogden, Lieutenant Arnold, Lieut Wade, Lieut Smith, Major Martin, and Sergeant Harvey. Lieutenant Nelson and Harding being absent when this picture was taken.], 44-verso
    - [Lieutenant Smith and Nelson eating breakfast], 45
    - Verso [: Lieutenant Smith and Nelson at breakfast; "Silent (?) (left) and Kirk, the daring North-American (right) having their first cup of coffee on American soil after Rounding the World in the air. They are here seen comfortably seated at breakfast at Ice Tickle, Lab (?) trailor., 45-verso
  - Subject files: First World Flight, 1924; 9 (Box 1544)
    - [The first memebers of the First World Flight gathered arounf a globe], 1
    - [Lifting the cruisers out of the Hughli River at Calcutta in Arden], 2
    - Verso [: Liting the cruisers out of the Hughli River at Calvutta in Arden to change from pontoons to wheels.], 2-verso
    - [The flagship of the German fleet at Scapa Flow], 3
    - Verso [: Looking down on the flagship of the scuttled German fleet at Scapa Flow.], 3-verso
    - [The First World Flight planes over the shore of the Gulf of Omon], 4
    - Verso [: Along the shore of the Gulf of Oman], 4-verso
    - [View of a shore from a First World Flight plane], 5
    - [First World Flight: junks boats in China], 6
    - Verso [: The finish of the flight from the United States to China.], 6-verso
    - [Shopkeeper in China-First World Flight], 7
    - Verso [:And shopkeepers left their shops.], 7-verso
    - [Two aviators in the First World Flight], 8
    - [Airplane from the First World Flight], 9
    - [Members of the First World Flight], 10
    - [Harbor at the base of snowy mountains-from the First World Flight], 11
    - [Two First World Flight planes over junk boats in China], 12
    - [Aviators in the First World Flight], 13
    - [Men involved in the First World Flight], 14
    - [Men involved in the First World Flight standing on a train], 15
    - [Plane sinking in the water (?)], 16
    - [Woman shaking hands with an aviator of the First World Flight], 17
    - [First World Flight planes over a coast], 18
    - [Officers (?)], 19
    - [People rowing in boats-from the First World Flight], 20
    - [Members of the First World Flight laying in snow], 21
    - [Two men involved in the First World Flight talking in front of the "Chicago"airplane], 22
    - [First World Flight planes flying over fields], 23
    - [Three First World Flight planes flying over a city], 24
    - [People in boats rowing out to greet the First World Fliers], 25
    - [Aviator in the First World Flight giving his autograph to a woman], 26
    - [First World Fliers surrounded by a group of people], 27
    - [First World Fliers surrounded by a crowd of people.], 28
    - [One of the First World Fliers], 29
    - [A crowd greeting the First World Fliers], 30
    - [A ship covered in ice-from the First World Fliers], 31
    - [First World Flight planes flying over mountains and houses], 32
    - [First World Flight plane sitting in water], 33
    - [People in Japan waving American flags to greet the First World Fliers], 34
    - [People in Japan waving American flags to greet the First World Fliers], 35
    - [First World Flight plane landing in the water near an iceberg], 36
    - [Lieutenant Smith and Nelson eating breakfast], 37
    - [A crane lifting a plane from the First World Flight out of the water (?)], 38
    - [An aviator (?) of the First World Flight walking across a stage], 39
    - [A view of the hills from a First World Flight plane], 40
    - [Malayan pygmies with a blowpipe], 41
    - Verso [They flew over the Malayan pygmies with their blowpipes and poison darts.], 41-verso
    - [Brids-eye view from one of the First World Flight planes.], 42
  Box 1545 - Box 1548
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  Box 1549 - Box 1552
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  Box 1553 - Box 1556
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  Box 1557 - Box 1560
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  Box 1561 - Box 1565
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6